<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: development | From the desk of Machiko Yasuda]]></title>
  <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-08-27T22:50:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Machiko Yasuda]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[day two - enter Firebase]]></title>
    <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/27/day-two-enter-firebase/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T21:41:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/27/day-two-enter-firebase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today:
&ndash; Did not go back into Cloudbees.
&ndash; Moved repository to GitHub instead, and started using a Node.js webserver for development.
&ndash; Hooked up Firebase to the Angular project and started adding items to Firebase database with my first controller.
&ndash; Wrote a few short JavaScript functions to (1) see how many items there are, (2) see how many are remaining and (3) calculate and show the progress.
&ndash; My model is as follows, at the moment: An array of item objects, which have a name (text) and status (true/false). False is not done. True means it&rsquo;s checked and done.</p>

<p>Road blocks:
&ndash; GUID URL generation and persisting into database. I will need to (1) create a new URL for each new checklist, (2) save that ID into the database with the array of items with statuses and names. When a user returns to that specific URL, the user will see that same list. It will not refresh and go blank (like it currently does).
&ndash; Have not done any test-writing yet. But I want to! I&rsquo;ve been writing in Sublime Text, console.log() into console and running the app. I would like to test, though.
&ndash; Down the line, we need to figure out how to deploy &ndash; Heroku or GitHub pages?</p>

<p>Tomorrow:
&ndash; I hope to set up testing somehow, with Jasmine, Karma or whatever.
&ndash; I hope to start saving and persisting data, even if I don&rsquo;t have unique URLs yet.</p>

<p>Code challenges:
&ndash; To make up for what I didn&rsquo;t do yesterday, I did a Ruby exercism.io and a JavaScript one.
&ndash; I will push them to GitHub as soon as they are approved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[day one - configuring]]></title>
    <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/26/day-one-configuring/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-26T11:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/26/day-one-configuring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Today:</h2>

<ul>
<li>Start CloudBees account with a basic Angular.JS build from Angular-Seed</li>
<li>It took a really long time.</li>
<li>Learned a little bit about ng-controller and ng-model, filters and directives.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Challenges:</h2>

<ul>
<li>I will have to generate unique URLs for each checklist. I&rsquo;m wondering how I&rsquo;ll do that&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tonight:</h2>

<ul>
<li>Watching this video on making real-time web apps with Angjuar.js and Firebase: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C7ZI7z7qnHU">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C7ZI7z7qnHU</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Code challenge of the day:</h2>

<p>-None. Yet. :(</p>

<h2>Life / Home:</h2>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m reading Flow by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi. Jeff Casimir, aka @J3, recommended the book during his presentation at LA Ruby the other month.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
