<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: deploying | From the desk of Machiko Yasuda]]></title>
  <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/deploying/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2013-09-06T10:49:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Machiko Yasuda]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day last - Deploying]]></title>
    <link href="http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/09/06/day-last-deploying/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-06T10:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pacific-escarpment-7101.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/09/06/day-last-deploying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>How to deploy an AngularFire &ndash; Yeoman project to GitHub</h2>

<ol>
<li>Follow these instructions at <a href="http://yeoman.io/deployment.html">Yeoman</a></li>
<li>If you get fatal CRLF errors, install <a href="http://linuxcommand.org/man_pages/dos2unix1.html">dos2unix</a>. Type into Terminal: <code>brew in]stall dos2unix</code> and then, use the tool to convert your troublesome files in the <code>dist</code> folder by running: <code>find /dist -type f -exec dos2unix {} +</code></li>
<li>Make sure that your <code>dist</code> folder is in the root directory.</li>
<li>After your <code>dist</code> folder is added to the <code>gh-pages</code> branch, push it by running: <code>git subtree push --prefix dist origin gh-pages</code></li>
<li>Go to <code>your-name.github.io/your-repo-name</code>]</li>
<li>Enjoy!</li>
</ol>


<h2>A weekly stand-up:</h2>

<h4>What I did this week &ndash;</h4>

<ol>
<li>Thanks to <strong>Theresa</strong> for having us over at her house this weekend. Climbing takes my mind off all the stress.</li>
<li>I worked on three roadblocks in my project: a Firebase refreshing problem and not getting tests to run and deploying.</li>
<li>Yesterday I went to a mini-Madison Ruby meet-up in LA. It&rsquo;s always fun to meet other web developers in the area that really care about the community, ethics and the future of the Internet in general.</li>
</ol>


<h4>Roadblocks I faced this week &ndash;</h4>

<ol>
<li>Thanks to <strong>Josh</strong> helped me fix my refreshing bug. <em>Takeaway</em>: If you&rsquo;re creating new Firebase collection upon a button click, <strong>separate the functions into different controllers</strong>.</li>
<li>Thanks to <strong>Delmer</strong> for helping me move Firebase call from the controller to the service. This helped me get Jasmine/Karma tests to run. <em>Takeaway</em>: <strong>Separate your Firebase into a service</strong>.</li>
</ol>


<h4>What&rsquo;s next &ndash;</h4>

<ol>
<li>Now that I&rsquo;ve deployed, I can start doing real testing on my phone and other people&rsquo;s non-iPhones. This will hopefully inform how I can continue to improve the user experience of typing, clicking, checking things off.</li>
<li>I also want to work on my datamap project and my personal portfolio page.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
